A Guide to the Virginia Guardsman Records, 1847-1949
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Guardman Records, 1847-1949
Library of Virginia
26194
4.8 cubic feet. 11 Hollinger Boxes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Office of the Adjutant General, Richmond, Va., on 3 October 1964.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Virginia Guardsman Magazine began in 1921 as the official organ of the Virginia National Guard published by the authority of the Military Board of Virginia under the office of the Adjutant General. Its first editor was Major Edwin P. Conquest, the State Inspector. During it's early years of publication, the magazine was a four-page semi-monthly publication. The magazine was distributed to officers and units of the Virginia National Guard, as well as the adjutant generals and state librarians of the United States. In June 1925, Major Bernard H. Baylor became Assistant to the Adjutant General following the death of Lt. Col. Joseph LeMasurier. At this time, Baylor also took over the duties as editor of the Virginia Guardsman. Baylor had enlisted in the Virginia National Guard on September 26, 1911, and served with the Richmond Howitzers on the Mexican Border in 1916. Baylor was also a commissioned officer in the Field Artillery during the first World War. The Virginia Guardsman was suspended in June 1929 then resumed in Apr. 1931 with an expanded format and monthly distribution. It was suspended again in Nov. 1933 and resumed semi-monthly in July 1934 due to a lack of funds. Finally, the Virginia Guardsman was suspended indefinitely in May 1939. The Virginia Guardpost is the current organ of the Virginia National Guard published quarterly since 1973.
Scope and Content Information
The records of the Virginia Guardsman are organized into three series with series designated for General Files, Publications, and Photographs. These records represent the work of Bernard H. Baylor, Editor of the Virginia Guardsman between 1925 and 1939. Baylor also served as Assistant to the Adjutant General beginning in 1925. The collection contains correspondence, memos, forms, photographs, publications, magazines, regulations, notes, and receipts.
Series I represents the General Files kept by the editor of the Virginia Guardsman, Bernard H. Baylor. It contains a substantial amount of correspondence to and from Baylor regarding a variety of issues affecting the publication. The correspondence is organized in two groups: one group is arranged chronologically and the other alphabetical by subject. The correspondence arranged chronologically consists of a wide variety of topics including submissions of articles, advertising in the magazine, and copyright. Most of the correspondence arranged by subject relates to acquiring photographs for Virginia Guardsman articles. There is also abundant correspondence with libraries throughout the country interested in receiving copies of the magazine. In addition to correspondence, this series contains a variety of other material kept by Baylor including newsclippings, memos, research notes, and other material used for research. A few items do not reflect Baylor's work on the Virginia Guardsman, but rather, his work as Assistant to the Adjutant General. Baylor organized the National Guard Field Meet in 1923-1924 and also served as U.S. Property & Disbursing Officer between 1927 and 1930.
Series II represents the Publications kept by Baylor for research purposes and general use. There are multiple copies of the Virginia Guardsman, but a complete run of the magazine is not present. Please note that bound copies of the publication between 1931 and 1939 can be found in the library stacks (UA500 V6). Early copies of the publication, however, are lacking. The magazine contains many informative articles on Virginia history, especially military history. It particularly documents the history of the Virginia National Guard in the 1930s. Other noteworthy publications in this series include out-of-state copies of National Guardsman publications, uniform and equipment catalogues, and both army and national guard regulation handbooks.
Series III is arranged alphabetically by folder title and represents Photographs many of which were used for publication in the Virginia Guardsman. The largest groups of photographs in this series are Civil War photos purchased from the Army Pictorial Service and images from the Virginia Guardsman. The Civil War photographs are arranged by locality when it was apparent. The Civil War photos were taken under the supervision of Matthew Brady and primarily document the destruction of Richmond. There are both general views of the city and specific localities such as Mayo's Bridge and the Tredegar Iron Works. Noteworthy images include: Benjamin F. Butler's Headquarters in Aitkens Landing, Va.; Christ Church in Alexandria, Va.; the McLean House in Appomattox, Va.; the Confederate Ram "Atlanta" (captured by Union troops); Forts Beauregard and Harrison; the fortifications at Petersburg, Va.; Castle Thunder and Libby prisons in Richmond, Va.; and the Moore House in Yorktown, Va.
The images from the Virginia Guardsman are arranged chronologically according to the issue they illustrate. In addition, the photographs are separated into two categories: used and unused images. Note that there is a separate finding aid which serves as an item level inventory of these photographs titled the "Guide to the Photographs of the Virginia Guardsman"). Those images used in the Virginia Guardsman include the page number of the issue on the Guide to these photographs. The images in the Virginia Guardsman illustrate articles and document events of the Virginia National Guard between 1931 and 1939. As a result, numerous historical images are included in this group of photographs. Additional Civil War photographs, engravings of Napoleon at Grenoble and Waterloo, portraits of past adjutant generals Samuel Cooper and William H. Richardson, the marriage bond of Edgar Allen Poe and Virginia Clemm, and lithographs from Ed. Beyer's "Album of Virginia" are just a few examples of the historic images used in the magazine. The majority of images, however, document contemporary events such as the celebration of George Washington's Birthday at Alexandria, a Confederate Reunion, re-enactment of the Battle of Chancellorsville, and the dedication ceremony at Stratford Hall. Images of Virginia Governors John Garland Pollard, George C. Peery, and James H. Price are well represented in this group. The remainder of the images from the magazine illustrate officers and soldiers in the Virginia National Guard.
Miscellaneous photographs interfiled alphabetically in this series include armories, camps, officers' portraits, soldiers training in the field, and images from World War I purchased from the U.S. Army Signal Corps. Noteworthy images here include the Richmond Howitzers Armory, a photo album showing Camp Stuart, a painting of Col. John H. Hamtramck of the 1st Regiment of Virginia Volunteers from 1847, and images of General John Pershing decorating troops in France during the First World War.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Each series is arranged alphabetically.
Organization
Organized into three series: Series I. General Files, 1914-1949; Series II. Publications, 1906-1924; Series III. Photographs, 1847-1939.
Contents List
- Series I: General Files, 1914-1949
  - Adjutant General 1927-1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (Chronological)
    - 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1931 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1932 - folder 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1932 - folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1933 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1935 - folder 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1935 - folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1936 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1937 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1938 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1942 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence (Alphabetical by Subject)
    - Army Pictorial Service (War Dept., Washington, D.C.), 1932-1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Cuts Loaned and Borrowed, 1932-1938 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Haines, E. Irvine, 1930-1936 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Libraries, 1931-1937 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Mailing List, 1928-1936 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Mailing List, 1937-1940 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Maps, 1931-1938 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Norfolk-Portsmouth Chamber of Commerce, 1931-1934 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Photographs, 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Photographs, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Photographs, 1935-1938 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Firing Data Forms (Blank), 1931 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Insignia (Virginia Engraving Co.), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - List of Photographs from the Signal Corps
    - 42nd Division, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 80th Division, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - List of World War Units and Corresponding Reconstituted Successor Units, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Medals, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Memos, 1928-1942 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1927-1939 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - National Guard Field Meet
    - folder 1 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - folder 2 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - News Clippings
    - 1914-1939 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Observation Forms for Field Artillery (Blank), 1928 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Outline of History of the 246th Coast Artillery, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Publication Forms (Blank), 1935 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Receipts, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Record of Monthly Attendance Drills, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Relative Rank of Officers in the Virginia National Guard, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Report of Funds, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Research Notes
    - 1925-1947 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - n.d. - folder 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - n.d. - folder 2 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Roster of Officers, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Property and Disbursing Officers, 1927-1930 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Vendor's Invoices (Blank), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Protective Force, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Warehouses, 1926-1933 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Series II: Publications, 1906-1944
  - Alcohohic Beverage Control Act, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - An Analysis of Physical Examinations for the C.C.C. at Richmond, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Army Regulations
    - Flags, Colors, Standards..., 1944 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Prescribed Uniform, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Catalogues
    - Associated Military Stores, 1929-1932 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Lilley Officers' Uniforms and Equipment, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Service Medals, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Check-List of Virginia State Publications, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Ceremonies Attending the Presentation of the Silver Service to the Battleship Virginia, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Classifications and Instructions of the Preparation of Budget Estimates, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Handbook of the 155mm Gun Materiel, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Illinois Guardsman, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Initial Muster Rolls, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Military Code of Virginia, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Military Laws of Virginia, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - National Guard News, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - National Guard Regulations, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - New York National Guardsman, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Pennsylvania Guardsman, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Price Lists from the Superintendent of Documents (Washington, D.C.), 1930-1941 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Recruiting News, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Regulations Concerning Duties of Employees, Official Superiors, Medical Officers, and Others, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Regulations Relating to Tax on Admissions, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Rewards for Service United States Army, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - "St. Peter's Church in New Kent Co. Virginia: It's History It's Restoration", 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Sketch of the Richmond Howitzers and Their Historic Home, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Softball Official Rules, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - United States Army Almanac, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Virginia Guardsman
    - 1931 April (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 1931 August (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 1931 December (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 1932 February (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 1932 July (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 1932 September (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 1933 January-February (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 1933 July-August (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - 1934 July (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 1934 August-September (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - 1934 October (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - 1935 January-February (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - 1937 January-December (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - 1938 January-March (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - 1938 April-December (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - VMI Alumni News, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Series III: Photographs, 1847-1939
  - Album of Virginia by Ed. Beyer, 1858 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - American Legion Post No. 16 (Lynchburg, Va.), n.d. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Armories
    - Exteriors, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Interiors, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Automobile, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Buttons, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Camps
    - Aerial View, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Camp Stuart (Richmond, Va.) (Photo Album), 1916 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Views, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Civil War (Brady Photos)
    - Aitkens Landing, Va. - B.F. Butler's Headquarters (Frazier House), n.d. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Alexandria, Va. - Christ Church, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Alexandria, Va. - Marshall House, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Alexandria, Va. - Old Dominion Bank, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Alexandria, Va. - Provost Marshall's Office, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Alexandria, Va. - Taylor's Tavern, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Appomattox, Va. - McLean House, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Appomattox, Va. - Captured Guns, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - City Point, Va. - Quartermaster Headquarters, ca. 1864-1865 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Confederate Ram Atlanta, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Drewry's Bluff, Va. - Obstructions in the James River, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Dutch Gap, Va. - Aitkens House, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Dutch Gap, Va. - Canal, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Dutch Gap, Va. - General View, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Fairfax, Va. - Fairfax Courthouse, 1863 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Fairfax, Va. - Fairfax Seminary, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Falls Church, Va., n.d. (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Fortifications - Fort Beauregard, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Fortifications - Fort Harrison, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - James River, va. - Residence, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - New Kent Co. - Poplar Grove Farm, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Petersburg, Va. - Fortifications, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Petersburg, Va. - Globe Tavern, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Petersburg, Va. - Grace Episcopal Church, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Petersburg, Va. - Poplar Grove Church, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Richmond, Va. - Arsenal (Ruins), ca. 1865 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Richmond, Va. - Capitol Building, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Richmond, Va. - Chritian Mission Building, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Richmond, Va. - Custom House, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Richmond, Va. - General Views, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Richmond, Va. - Governor's Mansion, ca. 1865 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Richmond, Va. - Lee House, ca. 1865 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Richmond, Va. - Mayo's Bridge (Ruins), 1865 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Richmond, Va. - Old Stone House, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Richmond, Va. - Pratt's Castle, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Richmond, Va. - Prisons - Castle Thunder, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Richmond, Va. - Prisons - Libby Prison, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Richmond, Va. - Residences, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Richmond, Va. - Ruins, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Richmond, Va. - Tredegar Iron Works (Ruins), 1865 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Richmond, Va. - Washington Equestrian Statue, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Richmond, Va. - Wharf, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Yorktown, Va. - Confederate Battery, 1862 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Yorktown, Va. - Moore House, 1862 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Holt, Senator Saxon Winston, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Lexington, Va. - Lee Chapel (Interior), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Locomotive, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Map of Eastern Virginia (35mm Negative), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Massenburg, George Alvin, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Officers
    - 1932 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - 1935 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Henderson, Major, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Hensley, Staff Sgt. Daniel B., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Hinson, Sgt. B.F., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Jackson, Capt. William B., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - James, Sgt. George L., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Lee, Brig. Gen. Fitzhugh, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Martin, Staff Sgt. Fletcher, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Nunally, Sgt. George L., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Waller, Adj. Gen. S. Gardner, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Waterbury, General, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Pageant, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Paintings
    - Battle of Trevilian Station, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Col. John H. Hamtramck, 1847 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Resolution in Appreciation to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1936 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Soldiers
    - 111th Field Artillery Regiment in Tobyhanna, Pa., 1932 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Gordonsville Maneuvers, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Group Photos, ca. 1911 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Parades, ca. 1930s (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Training Photos, ca. 1911 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Virginia Rifle Team, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - West Point Cadets Firing 8-Inch Railroad Guns, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - State Medals, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Tank of the 29th Tank Co. (includes 2 printing plates), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Unidentified Images, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Virginia Beach Archery Club, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Virginia Guardsman
    - 1831 April (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - 1831 August (Unused Images) (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - 1931 September (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - 1931 October (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - 1932 February (Unused Images) (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - 1932 April (Unused Images) (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - 1932 May - Used Images (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - 1932 May - Unused Images (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - 1932 June (Unused Images) (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - 1933 September (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - 1932 October - Used Images (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - 1932 October - Unused Images (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - 1932 November (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - 1932 December (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - 1933 January-February (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - 1933 March-April (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - 1933 May-June (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - 1933 July-August (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - 1933 September-November - Used Images (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - 1933 September-November - Unused Images (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - 1934 July (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1934 August-September - Used Images (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 1934 August-September - Unused Images (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - 1934 October (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - 1934 November-December (Unused Images) (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 1935 January-February - Used Images (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 1935 January-February - Unused Images (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - 1935 March-May - Used Images (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - 1935 March-May - Unused Images (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - 1935 June-July - Used Images (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - 1935 June-July - Unused Images (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - 1935 August-October - Used Images (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - 1935 August-October - Unused Images (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - 1935 November-December - Used Images (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - 1935 November-December - Unused Images (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - 1936 March-May (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - 1936 June-August (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - 1936 September-December (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - 1937 January-December - Used Images (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - 1937 January-December - Unused Images (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - 1938 January-March (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - 1938 April-December - Used Images (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - 1938 April-December - Unused Images (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - 1939 January-March (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Virginia National Guard Headquarters (Printing Plate), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - World War I
    - Field Artillery Practice at Camp Lee, Va., 1918 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - General Pershing - Decorating Colors of 115th Infantry, 29th Division, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - General Pershing - Major General C.G. Morton and Officers & Decorated Men Saluting Colors in Fresnes, France, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Leviathan which took 80th Division to France, ca. 1918 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Men of the 57th Brigade on Practice Hike, ca. 1918 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Twenty-Ninth Division - Training at Attention for Fieldpack Inspection, ca. 1918 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Twenty-Ninth Division - training Men Eating Lunch in Field, ca. 1918 (Box 9, Folder 32)
- Oversized Photographs
  - Armories
    - Alexandria Light Infantry, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Forty-Fifth St. Armory (Norfolk, Va.), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Grimes Battery (Portsmouth, Va.), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Lynchburg Home Guard, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Monticello Guard (?) (Charlottesville, Va.), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Richmond Howitzers - Gymnasium, ca. 1922 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Richmond Howitzers - Swimming Pool, ca. 1922 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Battery A Limber in Texas, ca. 1916-1917 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Building (Unidentified), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Camp (Unidentified), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Cooks
    - Baking Bread in Field - Clouse-Up, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Baking Bread in Field - Side View, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Near Supply Tent, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Firing Range, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Man Walking Dogs, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Richmond Howitzers
    - Alexandria Homecoming - After Breakfast, 1909 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Alexandria Homecoming - Before Breakfast, 1909 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Alexandria Homecoming - Harnessing Up at the Railroad Station, 1909 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Alexandria Homecoming - Unloading the Caissons, 1909 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Soldiers Outside of Armory, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Signal Corps, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Soldiers on Horseback, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Supply Wagon Train, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Vehicles
    - Motorcycle, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Quartermaster's Car & Truck, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 25)
- Oversized Documents
  - Blueprints
    - Dependable Depression Denters, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Police Range Target Butt, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Maps
    - Richmond and Its Environs, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Surry Quadrangle, 1919 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - New York Times Picture Section, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Outline of the History of the 111th Field Artillery, 1925 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Payrolls for Personal Services (Photostats), 1928 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Publications
    - La Vie Parisienne, 1922-1923 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Guardsman - 1928 January (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Guardsman - 1928 May (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Guardsman - 1928 June (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Guardsman - 1929 June (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Research Notes, 1934-1935 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Statement of the National Guard Fiels Meet, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 14)